The next thing I would like to discuss is putting the tattoo needle in the tattoo machine. Once it is removed out of its sterile package, it is going to look like this There is a small rubber grommet that is inserted into the back of the needle and that is to keep it stationary on the machine.
One little tattoo secrets is when you pull the needle out of the package, it is going to be straight.
With the needle down, you are going to want to slightly bend it so it is arced slightly and I will explain right now why that is.
Here is our tattoo machine.
You are going to want to hold it from the top and the bottom and insert the needle through the front and you can hold it with your fingers like such and you apply it onto the bar that is here.
Now it is stationary.
It can't really wiggle around.
Now you can see that it is arced down.
The reason we do that is as we install the needle tube, this is the reservoir in front of the needle that is going to hold the ink.
We are going to slide this up. Now you have to be extremely careful when you do this that the needle in the tip does not bang against the sides because it will dull it.
These are razor sharp needles and any burrs or anything like that will affect your tattoo in performance.
So as we bring it in, we are going to pull all the way back until the needle slightly pokes out from the front of the needle just a little bit.